export const TSquestion =  [
        {   id:1,
            question:'The command to compile a TypeScript file is:',
            options: ['Npm init', 'typescript -compile', 'tsc', 'jsc'],
            correctAnswer: 'tsc'
        },
        {   
            id:2,
            question:'A union type is a variable that can be assigned more than one type.',
            options: ['True', 'False', ],
            correctAnswer: 'True'
        },
        {   
            id:3,
            question:'How do you declare a variable with string type in typescript?',
            options: ['let var: String', 'let var = string', 'let var { string }', 'let var = { string }'],
            correctAnswer: 'let var: String'
        },
        {   
            id:4,
            question:'A tuple is a special type of array with a ________ size',
            options: ['Indefinite', 'Flexible', 'Fixed', 'Large'],
            correctAnswer: 'Fixed'
        },
        {   
            id:5,
            question:'The return type of a function is declared by typing',
            options: ['function func() { string; }', 'function func(): String { }', 'function func() = string',
                 'function string() { }'],
            correctAnswer: 'function func(): String { }'
        },        
        {   
            id:6,
            question:"You use _______ keyword when you don't want a variables value to be reassigned a value.",
            options: ['const', 'let', 'var', 'boolean'],
            correctAnswer: 'const'
        },
        {   
            id:7,
            question:'Modules are imported from external files with the ________ statement.',
            options: ['stdio.h', 'require', 'include', 'import'],
            correctAnswer: 'import'
        },
        {   
            id:8,
            question:'Modules are exported from different files with the ________ statement.',
            options: ['export', 'exclude', 'import', '<head>'],
            correctAnswer: 'export'
        },
        {   
            id:9,
            question:'let myname: string | null; is an example of:',
            options: ['nested objects', 'union literals', 'objects', 'interface types'],
            correctAnswer: 'union literals'
        },
        {   id:10,
            question:'let teacher = { name: "Zeeshan", experience: "10"} is a:',
            options: ['variable', 'const', 'tuple', 'object'],
            correctAnswer: 'object'
        },{
            id:11,
            question:'let myval: any; can be assigned the value of',
            options: ['String', 'Number', 'true', 'All of the above'],
            correctAnswer: 'All of the above'
        },{
            id:12,
            question:'An enum in TypeScript is typed as:',
            options: ['let enum = red;', 'let name:enum = { "Red" };', 'enum Color {Red, Green, Blue};', 
                'let red = enum;'],
            correctAnswer: 'enum Color {Red, Green, Blue};'
        },{
            id:13,
            question:'Complete this statement: ______________ = [ 2, 6 , 7 ]',
            options: ['let array1: number[]', 'let numbers:', 'let array1: string[]', 
                'let array[]: number'],
            correctAnswer: 'let array1: number[]'
        },{
            id:14,
            question:'You can assign the string type to the name parameter in this function by typing: function funcName( name______) { ... }  ',
            options: [':string', ':number', '= string', 'string[]'],
            correctAnswer: ':string'
        },{
            id:15,
            question:'The parameter in the following function is a: function funcName(name?: string){ ... }',
            options: ['special parameter', 'mandatory parameter', 'optional parameter', 'named parameter'],
            correctAnswer: 'optional parameter'
        },{
            id:16,
            question:'The _________ parameter a function to treat an indefinite number of arguments as an array',
            options: ['optional parameter', 'rest (...)', 'array parameter', 'named parameter'],
            correctAnswer: 'rest (...)'
        },{
            id:17,
            question:'A ________ is a function passed as an argument to another function.',
            options: ['class', 'async function', 'callback', 'tuple'],
            correctAnswer: 'callback'
        },{
            id:18,
            question:'array.push("value") _______ a value to/from an array.',
            options: ['adds', 'removes', 'shifts', 'replaces'],
            correctAnswer: 'adds'
        },{
            id:19,
            question:'A _______________ is essentially nested callbacks stacked below one another forming a pyramid structure.',
            options: ['Nested Array', 'Callback Hell', 'For loops', 'Javascript Promises'],
            correctAnswer: 'Callback Hell'
        },{
            id:20,
            question:'Pillar of OOP is/are :',
            options: ['Abstraction', 'Encapsulation', 'Inheritence', 'All of the above'],
            correctAnswer: 'All of the above'
        },{
            id:21,
            question:'Array._______ gives us a slice of the array.',
            options: ['slice()', 'sort()', 'shift()', 'reverse()'],
            correctAnswer: 'slice()'
        },{
            id:22,
            question:'type CarType = { string } is an example of:',
            options: ['Casting', 'Null', 'Type Alias', 'generics'],
            correctAnswer: 'Type Alias'
        },{
            id:23,
            question:'let func = () => { ... } is an example of: ',
            options: ['Callback', 'Tuple', 'Type Alias', 'Arrow Function'],
            correctAnswer: 'Arrow Function'
        },{
            id:24,
            question:'console.log(obj.key) is using:',
            options: ['Dot notation', 'Bracket notation'],
            correctAnswer: 'Dot notation'
        },{
            id:25,
            question:'The await keyword can only be used inside a _________ function.',
            options: ['Typescript', 'Async', 'Arrow', 'Promise'],
            correctAnswer: 'Async'
        },{
            id:26,
            question:'When a function does not return a value we use _______ type',
            options: ['String', 'Void', 'Number', 'Boolean'],
            correctAnswer: 'Void'
        }
    ]
    
